<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Jiahua Chen</title>
    <link>https://jiahua.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Jiahua Chen</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <copyright>Copyright © 2022, Jiahua Chen.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 22 Nov 2022 00:25:41 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jiahua.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Church Numerals in Ruby</title>
      <link>https://jiahua.io/writing/church-numerals-in-ruby/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jiahua.io/writing/church-numerals-in-ruby/</guid>
      <description>Church Numerals in Ruby A quick and dirty introduction to numbers in λ calculus, with a twist of Ruby.
Necessary Preface I have zero Ruby experience prior to this. All my Ruby knowledge comes from putting this together. However, Ruby has some very nice syntactic sugar with lambdas that I&amp;rsquo;ll take full advantage of. Try out some of the code blocks in irb! So, what syntactic sugar? Here&amp;rsquo;s some of the syntax that I use (and think is cool!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Connctme</title>
      <link>https://jiahua.io/projects/connctme/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jiahua.io/projects/connctme/</guid>
      <description>ConnctMe ConnctMe was presented at Hack@Home 2020, where it won &amp;ldquo;Best Use of Google Cloud&amp;rdquo;.
Inspiration Networking is hard, and COVID-19 has only made it harder. Keeping track of all of the people you&amp;rsquo;ve met and then remembering to follow up is exhausting. In the past, you could at least hand out your business card or copies of your resume to ensure that you&amp;rsquo;re remembered, but social distancing has made that a thing of the past.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Crowds</title>
      <link>https://jiahua.io/projects/crowds/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jiahua.io/projects/crowds/</guid>
      <description>Crowds Crowds was presented at Hack@Brown 2021, where it won the Wolfram Award.
Inspiration Apple and Google have developed private and secure exposure notification options within their ecosystems and operating systems. However, these systems are open to the general public and require pre-enrollment. Only a fraction of the population is enrolled and even fewer choose to report their exposures. Within a closed environment, such as a school, university or large office - there has to be a solution that complements existing preventative measures (for example, Brown tests on-campus populations biweekly) to provide richer exposure notifications and campuswide data while maintaining user privacy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Image Colorization</title>
      <link>https://jiahua.io/projects/image-colorization/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jiahua.io/projects/image-colorization/</guid>
      <description>Link
Abstract Over the last decade, there has been a lot of interest in the process of automated picture colorization for a variety of applications, including the restoration of old or deteriorated photos. Due to the high degrees of freedom in the assignment of color information, this problem is extremely ill-posed. Many recent advances in automatic colorization involve images with a shared theme or need highly processed data as input, such as semantic maps.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Modified SRI</title>
      <link>https://jiahua.io/projects/sleep-regularity-research/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jiahua.io/projects/sleep-regularity-research/</guid>
      <description>Research done while I was with Brown HCI lab in Fall, 2021.
Presented at the Brown Undergraduate Research Symposium in May, 2022.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pivot</title>
      <link>https://jiahua.io/projects/pivot/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jiahua.io/projects/pivot/</guid>
      <description>Pivot Pivot was presented at Ivyhacks 2020, where it won Best Multiplayer Product.
Inspiration Remote learning is becoming more and more prevalent in the wake of COVID-19, especially through Zoom. Unfortunately, many teachers have difficulty creating an interactive environment with Zoom: polling is frustrating to use, student questions get lost in the chat, and the &amp;ldquo;raise hand&amp;rdquo; feature disrupts the flow of lectures. In addition, a lot of students lack the powerful wifi connection required for Zoom, which means they might lose access to a lecture partway through.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Projects</title>
      <link>https://jiahua.io/projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jiahua.io/projects/</guid>
      <description>Here are some of my projects. I&amp;rsquo;m interested in creating designs and products that are both sustainable and innovative. Feel free to take a look around at my work!
Research Modified Sleep Regularity Index, Brown HCI Image Colorization, Computer Vision Project Hackathon Projects Pivot, Ivyhacks 2020 ConnctMe, Hack@Home 2020 Crowds, Hack@Brown 2021 </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
